Now in this lecture, we're going to take a look at how Amazon bedrock agents work step by step.
So first we have our end user John who is going to interact with our AI agent. Now let's take a
look at what his query is. So he wants the agent to book a hotel if his leave balance is
more than three days. So that's the user input. Now when you create an agent on the Amazon bedrock
agent framework, it will by default provide you with a prompt store. So what does this prompt store
contain? It will contain some default prompt templates and which will be customized based on
the large language model that you'll select for your agent. So if you use anthropic, then it's
going to have a different kind of a prompt template. If you use no one model from Amazon, then it's
going to have a different default prompt template. But you can also create your own custom prompt
template and store in this prompt store. Now, why do we have this prompt store? So before the final
prompt goes to the large language model driving the agent, the user input is augmented with more
details. So what are those details? First, we have the user input and this is our user input here.
Now next, we have the instructions that we provide to the agent. So now let's say we are creating
vacation planner agent and the job of that vacation planner agent is let's say if the user provides
an input, then you should be able to book a hotel, you should be able to book a flight and so on.
So you provide the agent some instructions on what is its domain. So those instructions are added
along with the user input. Next, we tell the large language model driving the agent,
what are all the tools available to the agent. So maybe you have access to airline APIs,
maybe you have access to better knowledge base, maybe you have access to hotel APIs. So all the tools
that agent has access to are provided as part of the prompt. And then we also provide details
about the guardrails. So when we combine all of these, we get the final prompt. So once we have
this final prompt, then there is further augmentation of this prompt. So what we have is also a session
store that is enabled when we create an agent in the Amazon bedrock service. So what is this
session store used for basically any previous interaction between the user and the agent at any
point of time, it summarizes all those conversations and then stores in the session store.
So when you have a new conversation, that is loaded as part of the prompt. So what would happen is
this conversation history would be added to this final prompt. So once that is done,
the prompt plus the conversation history would be sent to the large language model
driving the agent. Next, this agent is going to do the task decomposition or task planning
using reasoning and action style of planning. So let's say in our case, John wanted to book a
hotel if the leave balance is more than three days. So then this LLM is going to break it into
multiple tasks. Let's say it will say, okay, first check the leave balance, then if the leave balance
is more than three days, then go ahead and book a hotel. So that's how it's going to break down
the various tasks. Now once that is done, so it will use the tools that are integrated with this
agent. So maybe to check the leave balance, it will make a call to the HR system and then get a
response. And once it has that response, then response from the tool, also known as observation,
is shared with the agent along with the original prompt. So once these details are shared with
the agent, it will again do the task decomposition. Maybe this time it decides that we should
go ahead and book a hotel room. So it will again execute these tools and the observation from
these tools is then shared with the large language model driving the agent again. And this will
continue in the loop until the agent determines that the user query has been sufficiently
answered. And in that case, it's going to send the final answer to our end user saying that
this is the response to your query. Now if I broadly summarize the agent execution steps,
the first thing is user will provide an input or a question. And then this is going to be
augmented with further details from the prompt store. Next, it's going to fetch the conversation
history from the session store, then there are going to be some validations on the toxicity,
auto domain questions and so on. And then finally, we will have the orchestration style
prompting, which will do the planning tool execution and generate the final observation or
answer, which will be sent back to the user. I hope this is clear to you now on how Amazon
bedrock agents work. I'll see you in the next lecture. Thank you.